Susan Rindt, PsyD

Markdown -> PDF, HTML, and more http://github.com/drrindt/resume

SUMMARY

I am an independent consultant and clinician providing case consultation, training & education seminars, program development services and managerial oversight for several organizations. My clinical interests and expertise include: trauma (combat, personal sexual assault, child physical and sexual abuse); acute psychiatric disorders; grief and loss; substance abuse; relationship issues and communication patterns; anxiety and eating disorders; specific learning difficulties; and adolescent, developmental, and disorders of childhood.

I also maintain a private clinical practice while continuing to provide treatment services and consultation supervision in both hospital and community-based settings. At this time I provide individual, group, family and couples therapy, as well as psychological testing services to diverse populations.

EDUCATION

PsyD Clinical Psychology—FamilyTrack, March 2002

California School of Professional Psychology, San Diego, CA

MA Clinical Psychology, June 2000

California School of Professional Psychology, San Diego, CA

BSc (Hons) Psychology, First class distinction, June 1998

University of Stirling, Scotland, UK

Certifications

- ► Certified Prolonged Exposure Therapy Clinician
 - * Center for the Treatment & Study of Anxiety, University of Pennsylvania
 - * Supervisors: Edna Foa, PhD, Elna Yadin, PhD, and Elizabeth Hembree, PhD
- ► Certified Prolonged Exposure Therapy Trainer (in progress)
 - * Center for the Treatment & Study of Anxiety, University of Pennsylvania
 - * Supervisors: Edna Foa, PhD, Elna Yadin, PhD, and Elizabeth Hembree, PhD
- Additional specialist training in Cognitive Processing Therapy (VA San Diego) and EMDR (EMDR Institute, Inc)

CLINICAL EXPERIENCE

Clinical Director of Military Programs, April 2008—present

Contractor to Aurora Behavioral Healthcare, San Diego, CA

- ► Program development and management of intensive inpatient residential treatment program for active duty service members and their families
- Manage a staff of 15 directly and oversee operations of multiple other departments
- Provide direct therapy treatment for PTSD and co-occurring substance use disorders as well as multiple psychiatric and personality disorders
- ► Clinical supervision, education and training of licensed professionals working in this program

Clinical Experience SUSAN RINDT, PSYD

► Administrative duties including department accounting, case management, treatment team, utilization review, business development and assisting in personnel decisions

- Education, business development and community outreach services to FIXME: command military personnel in Western US
- ► Liaison between nursing staff, social work department, utilization review, psychiatrists, and the psychology department
- Liaison and collaboration with Triwest/Tricare and other government sponsored services for insurance fulfillment
- Research project development and trials on program efficacy and new treatment initiatives in conjunction with UCSD, VA, SDSU and location Military Treatment Facilities

Director of Psychology, April 2007—present

Contractor to Aurora Behavioral Healthcare, San Diego, CA

- ► Clinical supervision and training of 9 predoctoral and 3 postdoctoral interns in group therapy, individual therapy, psychological testing batteries, and initial assessment in an acute psychiatric population
- ► Group and individual therapy with acute inpatient and outpatient psychiatric patients
- Administrative duties including departmental accounting, case management, treatment team, utilization review, and assisting in personnel decisions.
- Liaison between nursing staff, social work department, utilization review, psychiatrists, and the psychology department

Clinical Private Practice/Hospital Consultant, August 2003—present

Locations: Coronado, CA — Del Mar, CA — Vista, CA

- ► Treatment modalities: Individual psychotherapy using a variety of therapeutic techniques including Cognitive Behavioral Therapy, family systems theory, and insight-oriented modalities. Brief therapy and long term models used where appropriate.
- Consulting and Training Services: Individual psychotherapy using a variety of therapeutic techniques including cognitive behavioral therapy, family systems theory, and insight-oriented modalities Brief therapy and long term models used where appropriate
- ► Hospital Privileges: Aurora Behavioral Health Care

Assistant Director of Psychological Services, August 2003—January 2004

Alvarado Parkway Institute, La Mesa, CA

- Clinical supervision and training of 6 predoctoral and 3 postdoctoral interns in group therapy, individual therapy, testing batteries, and initial assessment
- Group and individual therapy with acute inpatient and outpatient psychiatric patients
- ► Administrative duties including departmental accounting, case management, treatment team, utilization review, and assisting in personnel decisions.
- Liaison between nursing staff, social work department, utilization review, psychiatrists, and the psychology department

Psychological Assistant, August 2002—January 2003

Alvarado Parkway Institute, La Mesa, CA

- ► Group and individual therapy with acute psychiatric patients
- Training and supervision of psychology interns

General Experience SUSAN RINDT, PSYD

- Case management using a multidisciplinary team approach psychological testing batteries
- Liaison between nursing, social work, utilization review, psychiatrists, and psychology departments

Psychological Assistant, September 2001—August 2002

Switzer Center School, Torrance, CA

- ► Individual counseling with learning disabled and emotionally disturbed children and adolescents
- ► Case management
- ► Achievement and neuropsychological testing
- ► Individual education program development
- ► Parent and collateral contact liaison

Psychology Intern, July 2000—June 2001

Bayview Hospital, Chula Vista, CA

- ► Group and individual therapy with acute psychiatric patients
- Case management using a multidisciplinary team approach
- Psychological testing batteries

Psychology Practicum, August 1999—June 2000

EYE Crisis and Counseling, San Marcos, CA

- Individual and group therapy with children, adults, and families primarily involving issues of sexual abuse
- ► Psychological testing
- ► Administrative functions

GENERAL EXPERIENCE

Founding Member, Vice President and CFO, July 2011—Present

P.A.T.H.S., Psychiatric And Therapeutic Health Services, Inc., Del Mar, CA

- Managing partner of a clinical mental health corporation group practice serving primarily military spouses and families
- ► Developed programs and business/marketing strategies
- Management of clinical staff, education, supervision and training
- Responsible for clinical oversight, marketing, and day-to-day operations
- ► Financial management and accounting for corporation
- Liaison with Insurance Companies for provision of services and credentialing of staff

Assistant Manager, August 1989—March 1993

B & Q, Plc., Glasgow, Scotland, UK

- ► Personnel, administration, and systems manager
- ► Responsible for 70 staff and 54,000 sq. ft. of retail space
- Staff trainer. Education, development and training of all staff across all departmental teams

Teaching Experience SUSAN RINDT, PSYD

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Consulting Educator, August 2009-present

- ► Present a variety of education seminars and training on PTSD, Military Culture, Evidence Based Treatment Modalities, Research and Efficacy of clinical Programs
- Audiences include licensed professionals in the field of Psychology, Psychiatry, Social Services, Marriage and Family Therapy, Military Command, Active Duty, and VA providers and Staff

Teaching Assistant, August 1999—May 2001

California School of Professional Psychology (San Diego)

Dissertation Orientation, Developmental Psychology, Social Psychology

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Trauma Related Guilt Reduction (TRG-R): Adjunctive Guilt Treatment for OEF/OIF Service members with PTSD (2011). Sonya Norman, PhD, Kendall Wilkins, BA, Carolyn Allard, PhD, Susan Rindt, PsyD, and Julia Kusian, PsyD. University of California San Diego/VA San Diego Health Care System, San Diego State University, VA Center of Excellence in Stress and Mental Health, & Aurora Behavioral Health Care.

 Clinical treatment protocol addressing treatment resistant guilt in OIF/OEF combat service members

The Role of Attention Training for PTSD: Computerized Treatment for PTSD symptom reduction (2010). Nader Amir, PhD, Sonya Norman, PhD, & Susan Rindt, PsyD Center for understanding and treating anxiety, San Diego State University, University of California San Diego, and Aurora Behavioral Health Care.

Clinical treatment protocol for anxiety aspect of PTSD and the relationship to symptom severity

Efficacy of PTSD and Co-occurring Disorder treatments in the inpatient setting (2008-2013). Susan Rindt, PsyD, Julia Kusian, PsyD & Brittany Davis, PhD.

- Clinical Treatment protocols to assess and monitor efficacy of all PTSD, Substance Use, Cooccurring and Mood Disorder Programs Aurora Behavioral Health Care, San Diego, CA
- ► Clinical assessments, diagnosis and treatment longitudinal outcome study of over 700 OIF/OEF service members, pre and post treatment and 6 month, 1 year, 2 year and 5 year post treatment follow up

Sudden Sibling Loss: Reflections of Women on Their Experience During Adolescence (2001). Susan Rindt, PsyD. California School of Professional Psychology, San Diego

The Effects of Psychosocial Factors on Coronary Artery Bypass Surgery Outcome (1998). Susan Mulholland, BSc (Hons). University of Stirling, Scotland

AWARDS

San Diego Mental Health Community Honoree, 2010

► Individual Award for "Recognition For Development of Military Treatment Program"

Best 24-hr Military Treatment Program, 2010

Awarded to Aurora Behavioral Health Care, received on their behalf for inpatient program

BEST Scholarship, 1998—2000

BUNAC, London, UK

 Won \$10,000 scholarship for two years of post-graduate study in the United States from the British Universities North America Club (BUNAC)

Education Abroad Program (EAP) Participant, 1996—1997

University of Stirling, Scotland, UK

Won fully funded scholarship (tuition and expenses) to study psychology overseas at the University
of California, Irvine for one year

RECENT CERTIFICATIONS AND CONTINUING EDUCATION (PAST 5 YEARS)

Supervision II: Advanced Topics, Ethics and Law, June 2012

Military Cultural Competence, Feb 2012

Philosophy of Integrated Treatment, Dec 2011

Crisis Intervention for Co-Morbid and Complex Populations, Dec 2011

EMDR Basics Training Weekend 2, November, 2011

Dialectical Behavior Therapy Skills Training, (Marsh Linehan, PhD), Sept, 2011

EMDR Basic Training Weekend 1, June 2011

Foundations of Clinical Supervision, Dec 2009

Prolonged Exposure Therapy for Chronic PTSD, (Edna Foa, PhD) Nov 2009

Cognitive Processing Therapy for PTSD, (VA San Diego), Jan 2009

Addressing the Psychological Health of Warriors and Their Families, PTSD, Depression and TBI, Sept 2008

Prolonged Exposure Therapy for PTSD I, July, 2008

Risk and Resiliency Factors in PTSD, July 2008

PTSD and the difficult Client, using a Developmental Model, July, 2008

PTSD and Substance Abuse: Dual Diagnoses Overview and Treatment, June 2008

Cognitive Behavioral Interventions for PTSD, June 2008

Group Therapy and Assessment for PTSD, June 2008

Overcoming Barriers to PTSD Treatments, June 2008

From Counselor to Coach, Making the transition, April, 2008

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

American Psychological Association

British Psychological Society

California Psychological Association

San Diego Psychological Association

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

References available on request

A copy of this resume in pdf format is available at https://raw.github.com/drrindt/resume/master/resume.pdf